We can also use conditional statements like if statements in our list comprehension to make them even more powerful.
So before I had my squares right for num in range of 6, I printed out num times num.
What if I only wanted to do this for the even numbers?
I would use an F statement and a quick thing about the condition that we're going to use
Does everyone know what the modulo operation is?
Modulo?
Okay.
So I'll explain it very quickly.
Modulo operation is the remainder that you get from division.
So 6 modular to modular with this percentage sign.
It's going to be 0.
We want to check if our number is divisible by 2.
That's how we know that it's even.
But there's one little gotcha here.
We learned about truthiness yesterday, right?
And that we can quickly check the truthiness of something by passing it into bull.
So we know that positive numbers are truthy.
We know that negative numbers are truthy as well.
Which numbers are falsy and Python?
Zero.
So we want to check if 6 is modular to.
What if we forget to do an extra check and actually check if it's zero?
Well, this expression be truthy or falsy.
It'll be falsy, right?
If I check by passing this whole expression into two, it's falsy, right?
So what we actually want to check is if the number modular to is equal to zero.
This is a little kind of subtle bug that still gets me occasionally in my own programming.
So this is one of those cases where we want to explicitly check.
We're going to get the wrong result.
Okay, going back to our squares here.
And you can just go use the up arrow to scroll up in the in the ripple.
My conditional goes on the right side.
So first, I kind of, I have my result.
Next, I have my four loop.
And last, in the formula, I have my abstainment.
I put my condition here.
So based on what we learned above, how would I check?
How would I only return this if the numbers were even?
What would my expression be?
If non-module, you're not going to.
It goes to the quantity zero.
It goes quantity zero, right?
So that will only give me the even squares.
Let's say I had this list of even squares.
And I'm going to assign it to a variable so that I can work with that a little bit easier.
Knowing everything that we know now, we know that these even squares are integers.
How would we print out a comma separated list of these values as a string?
How can we combine these operations?
What are the different pieces?
How do we take a list and combine it into comma separated values?
The joint.
And what is on the left side of the joint equation?
The delimiter.
That's right.
What am I joining on?
We know that even squares is my list of numbers.
And that joint takes a list or a list comprehension, right?
A list comprehension returns a list.
So what am I looping over?
Yeah.
I can say, you know, four even square and even squares.
So what I'm looping over.
But I know that joint takes a list of strings.
We have a list of integers.
How do we make that conversion?
That's right.
That converts from any other type to its string representation.
So now we have a list of strings and we can call joint on it.
If I press enter here, we get a result.
It's kind of how you start thinking about putting some of these pieces together.